<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: command-line | nothing yet | knomedia]]></title>
  <link href="http://knomedia.github.io/blog/categories/command-line/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://knomedia.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-30T12:26:19-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://knomedia.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Jason Madsen]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[javantas for quick java projects]]></title>
    <link href="http://knomedia.github.io/blog/2013/01/16/javantas-for-quick-java-projects/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-16T21:38:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://knomedia.github.io/blog/2013/01/16/javantas-for-quick-java-projects</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the not so distant past I made a decision that I wanted to really force myself to get overly comfortable and proficient with vim. I took the plunge. I had a tough time at first, but as I look back, I&rsquo;m really glad I did it. I really enjoy vim. I realize there are other great options as well. I&rsquo;m not against others having their opinions on editors (or even IDE&rsquo;s for that matter). But for me, I&rsquo;m glad I made the jump.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve started in on a course that is requiring us to write Java. The natural choice then is to go back to using Eclipse. I&rsquo;m really comfortable with Eclipse, and recognize the power that it brings. But&hellip; I keep believing that I can get it all done just as quickly using the shell and vim. Add in <a href="https://github.com/msanders/snipmate.vim">snipmate</a>, <a href="https://github.com/wincent/Command-T">Command T</a> and the ability to write some shell scripts, and I think I&rsquo;ll be happy sticking with vim.</p>

<p>So this afternoon I took some time to build <a href="https://github.com/knomedia/javantas">javantas</a> a shell script that handles some of the cruft of starting a small java project.</p>

<div id='videoContent' style="padding-top:30px; padding-bottom:30px;">
  <video controls='controls' poster='http://knomedia.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/javantas_intro.jpg' width='700' height='525' >
    <source src='http://knomedia.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/javantas_intro.mp4' type='video/mp4' />
  </video>
</div>


<p>Give it a spin from the <a href="https://github.com/knomedia/javantas">Github Repo</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing yesman]]></title>
    <link href="http://knomedia.github.io/blog/2012/11/26/introducing-yesman/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-26T12:55:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://knomedia.github.io/blog/2012/11/26/introducing-yesman</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My quest to go all-in with vim continues to make progress. This progress was held up a bit with my recent work on C++ within the university. With all the cruft that surrounds C++ development a full featured IDE seemed tempting. So over the Thanksgiving break I spent some time working on yesman (available at <a href="https://github.com/knomedia/yesman">GitHub</a>). Yesman is a command line application that will create and manage your C++ projects including unit testing. It will create a project, download and compile <a href="http://code.google.com/p/googletest/">Google Test</a>, and help you stub out C++ classes, headers and testing fixtures.</p>




<div id='videoContent' style="padding-top:30px; padding-bottom:30px;">
  <video controls='controls' poster='http://knomedia.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/yesman_poster.png' width='700' height='437' >
    <source src='http://knomedia.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/yesman_introduction.mp4' type='video/mp4' />
  </video>
</div>




<p>It is not quite finished. Future versions of yesman will include a system that allows you to build your c++ project through yesman using a managed make build process. Feel free to fork, tweak give feedback at the <a href="https://github.com/knomedia/yesman">GitHub repo</a></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
